Guide to the North African Jewish Manuscript Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Marrakech, 1825-1862; Series IV
  - Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti and the Benisti family
    - Document concerning a loan to a man from the village of Abra, 1906; MS.1825.0551; 4 pages (2 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Place: Abra. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti gave the man thirty doros to start a business. The document is signed by Aharon ben Abbu and Shelomoh ben Yosef Knafo.
    - Document concerning a loan to a man in Tamzart, 1906; MS.1825.0552; 4 pages (3 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Place: Tamzart. Shelomoh ben Mosheh 'Asor received 100 doros from Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti to start a business. The document is signed by Aharon ben Abbu and Shelomoh ben Yosef Knafo.
    - Document regarding a loan to Yehudah ben Yosef Oahnuna, 1898; MS.1825.0560; 4 pages (3 blank); 19 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti provided the loan. The document is signed by Avraham Gabai and Mosheh Hazan.
    - Document regarding a loan to Aharon Dayan, 1892; MS.1825.0561; 4 pages (3 blank); 19 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah Benisti gave Aharon Dayan ten doros to start a business. The document is signed by [?] Azuelos and David Botbol.
    - Document regarding a loan to Hayim ben Yissakhar Znati, 1909; MS.1825.0562; 4 pages (3 blank); 11 x 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti gave the loan to Hayim ben Yissakhar Znati of Fès. Signed by Yosef Pinto and Aharon ben Abbu.
    - Document regarding a loan to Yehudah ben Yosef Ouahnuna, 1898; MS.1825.0564; 4 pages (2 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti provided the loan. The document is signed by Yosef Hayim Perets and Aharon ben Abbu.
    - Document with regard to a man from the village of Ein-Nfad, 1909; MS.1825.0565; 4 pages (2 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Place: Marrakech. Yaakov ben Shelomoh Ouahnuna received money from Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti. Signed by Yosef Pinto and Aharon ben Abbu.
    - Document regarding a loan to Haviv ben Avraham Azulai from Ayt Agant, 1900; MS.1825.0570; 4 pages (3 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti provided the loan. Signed by Yosef Hayim Perets and Shelomoh ben Yosef Knafo.
    - Document relating to Yitshak Karisa from Ayt Agant, 1899; MS.1825.0571; 4 pages (1 blank); 19 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti provided the loan. Signed by Yosef Pinto and Shelomoh ben Yosef Knafo.
    - Document regarding a loan to Haviv ben Avraham Azulai from Ayt Agant and Mosheh Abuzaglo, 1898; MS.1825.0572; 4 pages (3 blank); 19 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti provided the loan. Signed by Shelomoh ben Yosef Knafo and Shimshon Binyamini.
    - Document relating to Ayosh ben Mosheh Biton from Ayt Agant, 1910; MS.1825.0573; 4 pages (2 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti provided the loan. Signed by Aharon ben Abbu and Maimon [?].
    - Document regarding a loan to Haviv ben Avraham Azulai from Ayt Lazghar, 1904; MS.1825.0574; 4 pages (3 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti provided the loan. Signed by Yosef ben Mosheh Pinto and Shelomoh ben Yosef Knafo.
    - Document regarding a loan to Shelomoh Waknin from Ayt Agant, 1912; MS.1825.0580; 4 pages (2 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti provided the loan. Signed by Aharon ben Abbu.
    - Document regarding a loan to Mosheh Khalfon ben Kikha, 1912; MS.1825.0581; 4 pages (2 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti provided the loan. Signed by Shelomoh Dayan and Haviv Asulin.
    - Document regarding a loan to Masud ben Shalom Waknin, 1912; MS.1825.0586; 4 pages (1 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Document regarding a prozbol to permit the continuation of debts beyond the Sabbatical year, 1896; MS.1825.0587; 1 leaf; 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 10)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti requested a ruling that the Sabbatical year would not cancel repayments according to previous loan agreements. Signed by Yosef Nahamias and Yitshak [?].
    - Document concerning a loan to Freha, the widow of Laziz Wahnun, 1899; MS.1825.0588; 1 leaf; 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 10)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti provided the loan. The document is signed by Shelomoh Smaja and David [?].
    - Legal document relating to the sale of an apartment, 1902; MS.1825.0781; 4 pages (3 blank); 19 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 11)
      Place: Marrakech. Shelomoh Benisti is mentioned. Signed by Mosheh Mizrahi and one other.
    - Legal document, 1921; MS.1825.0784; 2 pages; 25 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 11)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti is named in the document. The name Lazama is also mentioned.
    - Legal document, 1902; MS.1825.0788; 4 pages (3 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Legal document, 1909; MS.1825.0793; 4 pages (2 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 12)
      Place: Marrakech. Names mentioned include Shimon Abuzaglo, Hananyah Benisti and Salam Atarzman.
    - Legal documents with regard to the sale of property, 1917, 1921, 1924; MS.1825.0794; 4 pages (2 blank); 29 centimeters. (Box 33, Folder 3)
      Place: Marrakech. On one side of the page are two documents signed by Yosef ben Mosheh Biton and Yaakov ben Shelomoh Benisti and others. On the other side of the page is a separate legal document in Judeo-Arabic, written in 1924, signed by Yaakov ben Amram Vanunu and Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti.
    - Legal document, 1919; MS.1825.0797; 2 pages; 25 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 12)
      Place: Marrakech. The document mentions Yitshak ben Haviv Benisti, Yishayah Vizman and Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti. It is signed by Yosef Pinto, Mosheh Mizrahi and Shelomoh Hayim.
    - Legal document, 1917; MS.1825.0802; 4 pages (3 blank); 23 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Legal document, 1922; MS.1825.0804; 4 pages (2 blank); 29 centimeters. Damaged, with some loss of text. (Box 33, Folder 4)
      Place: Marrakech. Signed by Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti, Yisrael ben Avraham Gabai, Haviv Asulin and Aharon ben Abbu.
    - Legal document, 1907; MS.1825.0805; 4 p (3 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 13)
      Place: Marrakech. Signed by Yehuda ben Mosheh Abuzaglo, Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti, Aharon ben Abbu, and Masud Tanzi.
    - Legal document, 1919; MS.1825.0806; 2 pages; 24 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 13)
      Place: Marrakech. Signed by Mosheh Biton, Shelomoh Benisti, Aharon ben Abbu, Haviv Asulin and Yaakov Yosef Toledano.
    - Legal document relating to [Yaakov ben Yitshak Kabisa?], 1904; MS.1825.0807; 2 pages; 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 13)
      Place: Marrakech. Signed by Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti, Yosef Pinto, and Shelomoh ben Yosef Knafo.
    - Legal document relating to Avraham ben Yitshak [Karisa or Kabisa?], 1906; MS.1825.0808; 4 pages (2 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 14)
      Place: Marrakech. Signed by Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti, Aharon ben Abbu, and Shelomoh ben Yosef Knafo. The village of Ayt Agant is mentioned.
    - Legal document, 1919; MS.1825.0809; 4 pages (3 blank); 19 centimeters. Torn at folds. (Box 9, Folder 14)
      Place: Marrakech. Regarding a man from the village of Tamzart. Signed by Hananyah Benisti and [Haviv Asor?].
    - Legal document, 1922; MS.1825.0810; 4 pages (3 blank); 29 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 14)
      Place: Marrakech. Signed by Yisrael ben Avraham Gabai, Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti, Haviv Asulin, and Aharon ben Abbu.
    - Legal document, 1912; MS.1825.0811; 2 pages; 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 15)
      Place: Marrakech. Signed by Avraham ben Mosheh Biton, Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti, Shelomoh ben Yair and Mosheh Mizrahi.
    - Legal document, 1928; MS.1825.0812; 1 leaf; 25 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 15)
      Place: Marrakech. Names included in the document are: Yosef Biton, Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti, Masud Biton, and Mosheh Abuzaglo.
    - Legal document relating to David ben Mosheh Biton from the village of Ayt-Agant, 1900; MS.1825.0813; 4 pages (2 blank); 19 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 15)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti is mentioned in the document.
    - Legal document relating to Yehuda Abouzaglou, 1921; MS.1825.0815; 4 pages (2 blank); 25 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 16)
      Place: Marrakech. Other names mentioned in the document are: Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti, Haviv Asulin, and Aharon ben Abbu.
    - Document relating to the division of the property of Shelomoh Benisti among his seven sons, 1932; MS.1825.0819; 4 pages (2 blank); 30 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 16)
      Place: Marrakech. The sons are: Eliyahu, Hananyah, Mordekhai, Yosef, Yitshak, Yaakov, and Haviv. Signed by Mosheh Zrihen, Shelomoh Dayan, and one other.
    - Legal document, 1909; MS.1825.0879; 4 pages (3 blank); 23 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 16)
      Place: Marrakech. Signed by David Biton, Yosef Pinto, Aharon ben Abbu, and Hananyah Benishti.
    - Document of ownership of property, 1862; MS.1825.1151; 4 pages (3 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 17)
      Place: Marrakech. Document confirming the ownership of property of Yehudah ben Mosheh Abuzaglo, a resident of Ayt-Agant, who purchased it from Hananyah Benisti. The document is signed by David Saban.
    - Document regarding a business transaction, 1925; MS.1825.1153; 4 pages (2 blank); 18 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 17)
      Place: Marrakech. The people involved are Makhluf ben Shelomoh Kohen and Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti. The document is signed by Haviv Asulin and Meir Azwelos.
    - Document in Judeo-Arabic regarding financial matters, 1902; MS.1825.1231; 4 pages (3 blank); 23 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 17)
      Place: Marrakech. Shelomoh Benisti and Avraham Azulai from the village Ayt Tagant are mentioned. Signed by Aharon ben Abbu and one other person.
    - Two documents regarding a partnership, 1911; MS.1825.1233; 4 pages (2 blank); 23 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 18)
      Place: Marrakech. The first document is concerning a partnership between brothers of the Benisti family from Marrakech and signed by Mosheh Zrihen and another person. The second document is written by Hasibah, the wife of Eliyahu Benisti, to the two brothers mentioned above.
    - Document concerning a debt, 1893; MS.1825.1240; 4 pages (3 blank); 20 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 18)
      Place: Marrakech. The debt is owed to Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti by Yosef Amar. The document is signed by Haviv Asulin and Yeshayah Harosh.
    - Two documents concerning debts, 1893; MS.1825.1242; 4 pages (2 blank); 24 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 18)
      Place: Marrakech. The first document is regarding a debt owed by Haviv ben Maimon Asulin to Hayim Znati from Fès. The first document is signed by Mosheh ben Lulu and Haviv Asulin.The second document concerns a debt owed by Shelomoh Benisti to Hayim Znati.
    - Document concerning a financial transaction, 1899; MS.1825.1245; 4 pages (3 blank); 23 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 19)
      Place: Marrakech. Funds for the purpose of investment was given by Shelomoh Benisti to Yosef ben Mosheh Biton. The document was signed by Yosef Pinto and Aharon ben Abbu.
    - Two documents concerning loans, 1894, 1895; MS.1825.1246; 4 pages (2 blank); 19 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 19)
      Place: Marrakech. The first document is concerning money borrowed by Haviv ben Shelomoh ben Lulu from Hayim Znati from Fès. The document is signed by [Yosef Ilkhukhan?] and another person. The second document involves money given by Hayim Znati to Hananyah Benisti. The document is signed by Haviv Asulin.
    - Document regarding a partnership, 1894; MS.1825.1247; 2 pages; 23 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 19)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti transferred funds to Hayim Znati and his wife in order to form a business partnership. The document is signed by Yosef Pinto and Yosef Hayim Perets.
    - Document regarding the purchase of oil, 1892; MS.1825.1248; 4 pages (2 blank); 21 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 20)
      Place: Marrakech. The oil was purchased by Hananyah Benisti and Yosef Ohanina. The document is signed by Yaakov Ben-Hayim and Yehudah Shoshanah.
    - Document regarding a financial transaction, 1900; MS.1825.1250; 4 pages (3 blank); 24 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 20)
      Place: Marrakech. The money was given to Shalem ben Hayim Benisti and Haviv ben Avraham Azulai by Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti. The document is signed by Shelomoh Ben Yosef and another person.
    - Document regarding a financial transaction for a business, 1901 or 1902; MS.1825.1253; 4 pages (3 blank); 23 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 20)
      Place: Marrakech. The money was received by Haviv ben Avraham Azulai and David ben Mosheh Biton, both from the village of Ayt Aghant, from Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti. The document is signed by Yosef Pinto and Shelomoh ben Yosef ha-Kohen.
    - Document regarding a financial transaction, 1903; MS.1825.1255; 4 pages ( 2 blank, a portion of which is missing); 24 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 21)
      Place: Marrakech. The money was received by Shalem ben Masan Ben Shafat ha-Levi (also called L-Zbabri) and Shalem ben Masoud ibn Shimon (also called Gherbal) from Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti.
    - Document regarding a financial transaction, 1904; MS.1825.1257; 4 pages (3 blank); 23 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 21)
      Place: Marrakech. The money was given by Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti to Haviv ben Avraham Azulai from the village of Ayt L-zgher. The document is signed by Yosef Pinto and Shelomoh ben Yosef.
    - Document that confirms receipt of money, 1907; MS.1825.1258; 1 leaf; 12 x 19 centimeters. The bottom half of the page is missing. Some loss of text. (Box 9, Folder 21)
      Place: Marrakech. The money was given to Avraham ben Yosef Tangi from the town of Ouarzazat by Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti. The document is signed by Yosef Pinto and Avraham Gabai.
    - Document regarding a partnership, 1913; MS.1825.1263; 4 pages (2 blank); 19 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 22)
      Place: Marrakech. The partnership is between Avraham ben Mosheh Biton from the village of Ayt Tagant who received money from Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti. The document is signed by Aharon Ben Abbu and [?] Merciano.
    - Document regarding a business transaction, 1909; MS.1825.1266; 4 pages (2 blank); 19 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 22)
      Place: Marrakech. The document is written by Yosef ha-Kohen from the village of Iwnit to Hananyah Benisti who loaned him money for a business. The document is signed by Salim Vizman and Avraham Ohayon.
    - Document attesting to a purchase that was completed, 1915; MS.1825.1267; 4 pages (2 blank); 23 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 22)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti paid Shimon ben Akkan Abuzaglo from the village of Ayt Aghant for the purchase. The document is signed by Haviv Asulin and another person.
    - Document concerning a business transaction, 1912; MS.1825.1268; 4 pages (2 blank); 19 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 23)
      Place: Marrakech. Yosef ben Mosheh Biton from the village of Ayt Aghant received money from Yitshak ben Shelomoh Benisti. The document is signed by Aharon Ben Abbu and Salim Vizman.
    - Document regarding a purchase, 1916; MS.1825.1269; 4 pages (2 blank); 20 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 23)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah Benisti paid Shimon ben Yaakov Abuzaglo for the purchase. The document is signed by Aharon Ben Abbu and [?] Vanunu.
    - Document concerning cancellation of a claim, 1911; MS.1825.1270; 4 pages (2 blank); 23 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 23)
      Place: Marrakech. The document is written by Eliyahu ben Shelomoh Benisti to several people. The document is signed by Avraham Semmama and Mosheh ha-Kohen.
    - Document regarding a financial transaction, 1919; MS.1825.1274; 2 pages; 25 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 24)
      Place: Marrakech. The document concerns money that Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti gave to Mosheh ben Yosef Ezran from the village of Guinsayne. The document is signed by Aharon Ben Abbu and Mosheh Harosh and certified by Yaakov Toledano.
    - Document in Judeo-Arabic regarding a warning to Eliyahu Benisti, 1901; MS.1825.1275; 1 leaf; 19 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 24)
      Place: Marrakech. The warning to Eliyahu Benisti was delivered by his brother Hananyah Benisti. The warning concerns a room rented by Eliyahu Benisti. The document is signed by Shelomoh Ben Yair and Haviv Yifrah.
    - Document attesting to a transfer of funds, 1914; MS.1825.1277; 4 pages (2 blank); 19 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 25)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah Benisti gave money to Hananyah Vanunu for a business deal. The document is signed by Yosef Pinto and Shelomoh ben Yosef.
    - Document attesting to a transfer of funds, 1892; MS.1825.1279; 4 pages (2 blank); 23 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 25)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti gave money to David ben Mosheh Biton from the village of Ayt Aghant. The document is signed by Mosheh Pinto and Avraham Gabai.
    - Document regarding the rental of real estate, 1901; MS.1825.1280; 4 pages (3 blank); 19 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 25)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah Benisti rented a portion of a courtyard from Yehudah Edre'i. One of the signatories on the document is Shimshon bar Manoah Binyamini.
    - Bill of sale of vineyards located in the gardens of Ayt Sliman, 1903; MS.1825.1282; 1 leaf; 23 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 26)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti sold the vineyards to Akhan ben Masan Alfasi. Signed by Shelomoh Ben Yosef and David [?]
    - Document regarding a financial transaction, 1916; MS.1825.1283; 4 pages (2 blank); 15 x 16 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 26)
      Place: Marrakech. Yosef Biton received money from Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti for a business deal. The document is signed by Aharon Ben Abbu and Yosef [?]
    - Document regarding a financial transaction, 1918; MS.1825.1284; 1 leaf; 19 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 26)
      Place: Marrakech. David Zraf received money for a business deal from Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti. The document was signed by Aharon Ben Abbu and Yosef [?]
    - Document regarding a business transaction involving olives, 1918; MS.1825.1285; 4 pages (1 blank); 23 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 27)
      Place: Marrakech. Yosef ben Mosheh Biton and his brother Avraham, residents of Ayt Aghant, and Yosef ben Mosheh Abuzaglo, a resident of Ourika, sold olives and received 800 doros. The document is signed by Aharon Ben Abbu, Haviv Yifrah and Aharon Ben Haviv.
    - Bill of sale for a store, 1908; MS.1825.1286; 4 pages; (3 blank); 19 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 27)
      Place: Marrakech. Akhan Alfasi sold a store to Hananyah Benisti. The document is signed by Yaakov Dabila.
    - Document regarding a dispute over the harvest of olives, 1919; MS.1825.1288; 4 pages; (2 blank); 21 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 27)
      Place: Marrakech. The dispute was between Avraham ben Shimon Dadon, a resident of Tamzart, and Ayush Biton. The dispute concerned the harvest of olives that they purchased from Hananyah Benisti. The document is signed by Yosef Nahmias and one other.
    - Document regarding a financial transaction, 1918; MS.1825.1290; 4 pages; (2 blank); 23 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 28)
      Place: Marrakech. The document was written by David and Avraham, the sons of Mosheh Biton from the village of Ayt Aghant, who received money from Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti. The document is signed by Yosef Pinto and another person.
    - Document attesting to a joint purchase of a mule, 1921; MS.1825.1291; 4 pages; (2 blank); 21 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 28)
      Place: Marrakech. Masoud ben David ha-Kohen and Hananyah ben Shelomoh Benisti formed a partnership to purchase the mule. The document is signed by David Kohen and a member of the Azulai family.
    - Letter from Shelomoh Belforte, the owner of a publishing house, to Meir Benisti in Marrakech, 1921; MS.1825.1293.1-.4; 4 leaves; 28-29 centimeters. One is torn in the middle, with loss of text. (Box 9, Folder 29)
      Place: Livorno, Italy. Attached to the letter are three lists of books that were sent from Livorno to Marrakech.
    - Document regarding a financial transaction, 1921; MS.1825.1294; 4 pages (2 blank); 27 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 30)
      Place: Marrakech. Hananyah Shelomoh Benisti gave money for a business to David ben Mosheh Biton. The document is signed by Shelomoh Asabag and a member of the Azulai family.
    - Document in Judeo-Arabic regarding a sale of olives, 1921; MS.1825.1295; 2 pages; 22 centimeters. (Box 9, Folder 30)
      Place: Marrakech. The people involved in the transaction were David ben Yitshak Perets, Ayush ben Mosheh Biton from Tamzart, Masoud Dadon and Hananyah Benisti. The document is signed by Aharon Abbu.
  - Marrakech (general)
    - Midrash Peli?ah and other texts, Circa 1880-circa 1920; MS.1825.0008; Approximately 160 pages; 14 centimeters. (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Place: Marrakech. This manuscript consists of twelve consecutive texts bound together. The longest and the most important is Midrash Peli?ah, written by Yosef [last name unknown]. It appears as number 1, number 5, and number 9, with other texts interspersed. Besides Midrash Peli?ah are other texts in Hebrew and three in Judeo-Arabic: number 3, number 4 and number 8. One interesting text is a homily of Avraham Azulai, probably the father or the son of Hayyim Joseph David Azulai, 1724-1806 (ha-H?ida). The date and place of this manuscript is unknown, but there is no doubt that it was copied in the nineteenth century. Based on the names in the manuscript it appears that the manuscript is from Marrakech. The custom of giving money to children on Purim and on the ninth of Av, which is customary only in Marrakech, is mentioned in the manuscript.
    - Certificate for ritual slaughterer, 1921; MS.1825.0033; 2 pages; 18 centimeters. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Place: Dimnāt. Diploma of Avraham Rovigo certifying his qualification to serve as a ritual slaughterer, written in the community of Dimnāt in the year 5681 [1921], signed by the rabbis David ben Makhluf Zohar, Yosef ben Mas'ud Dahan, and others.
    - Legal document concerning real estate transaction, 1937; MS.1825.0036; 4 pages (2 blank); 30 centimeters. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Place: Marrakech. A legal document concerning a dispute over the sale of a courtyard. Signed by Moshe Zrihen, the president of the rabbinic court of Marrakech, July 30, 1937.
    - Legal document concerning real estate transaction, 1935; MS.1825.0037; 4 pages (3 blank); 30 centimeters. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Place: Marrakech. A legal document concerning a courtyard signed by Moshe Zrihen, the president of the rabbinic court of Marrakech, 24 December 1935.
    - Legal document concerning a courtyard and other real estate, 1864; MS.1825.0047; 1 leaf; 23 centimeters. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Place: Marrakech. Agreement between Yaakov Pariente and his uncle Yonah ben Yosef Pariente concerning a courtyard and other real estate. The document is signed by the rabbi Shemuel Yaakov. This rabbi, who was well-known through his oral teaching to students (including Avraham Abitbol), was not known to have written other documents.